SCOTT GELEAS

Alton, NH 03809

Phone: (603)-455-1657 | Email: scottgeleas97@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/scottgeleas | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/scottgeleas/

Portfolio: https://scottgeleas.github.io/React-Portfolio/

SUMMARY

Web Developer bringing experience in teamwork, multitasking, and attention to detail.

Group-minded, with a focus on completing tasks to ensure objectives are always met. Recently completed a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from University of New Hampshire, where experience was gained working in small groups to create professional-looking applications that developed a variety of technical skills and concepts. Have been recognized two times in a previous role for the work quality and performance (5-Star Supplier Excellence Award).

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, CSS3, HTML5,

Applications: GitHub, Heroku, Insomnia, MongoDB Compass, MySQL Workbench, MacOS, Windows **Tools:** React.js, GraphQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Express.js, Node.js, Handlebars.js, jQuery, Bootstrap, Jest

PROJECTS

Code Break

https://github.com/scottgeleas/Code-Break https://code-br.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: A full stack web application that allows users to save code snippets. Users can view and comment on other users' code snippets.
- Role: Backend GraphQL and some frontend components.
- Tools: React.is, GraphQL, Mongoose, MongoDB, Robo 3T, MongoDB Atlas, Node.is.

Restful Cabin Retreats

https://github.com/scottgeleas/Restful-Cabin-Retreatshttps://restful-cabin-retreats-sig.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: A full stack web application that allows users to 'rent' cabins from around the world. Users
 have the ability to 'reserve' a cabin after a user has created an account. A MySQL database was
 used with Sequelize to store the data needed.
- Role: Backend Database Modeling and Routes
- Tools: Node.js, Express.js, SQL, Sequelize, MySQL Workbench, Handlebars.js, and Flatpickr.js.

Book Search

https://github.com/scottgeleas/Book-Searchhttps://book-search-sjg.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: An application that allows users to search and save books that they want to read. This app uses the Google Books API.
- Role: GraphQL Backend.
- Tools: GraphQL, React.js, Mongoose, MongoDB, Robo 3T, MongoDB Atlas, Node.js

EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant 2021 – Present Trilogy Education Remote

Responsible for assisting students learning full stack web development. Providing support for students via office hours. Keeping class materials updated and resolving issues with software installations. Taking attendance and grading team projects.

Key Accomplishments:

 Facilitated student success in learning new technologies quickly while keeping up with strict timeframes for demonstrating new concepts which resulted in superb feedback from students regarding instructor support during class.

Mechanical Assembler 2017 – 2020 Milpower Source Belmont, NH

Responsible for receiving and inventorying incoming products. Utilizing teamwork and various tools to assemble power supplies. Testing finished products, labeling, and packaging them for shipment.

Key Accomplishments:

- 5-Star Supplier Excellence Award from Raytheon 2019 & 2020
- Inventoried and built products to ensure they were delivered on time and in the correct quantities to our armed forces.
- Contributed to a team of five by facilitating the assembly and shipping of products while jumping in to accomplish any other team goals that needed to be met on a daily basis to ensure customer satisfaction.

Laborer 2016 - 2017

Currier Construction Remodeling

Farmington, NH

Responsible for keeping product handy for workers to grab and go, keeping jobsite clean, and minor construction duties.

Key Accomplishments:

- Ensured worker safety by setting up staging and ladders in specific locations on the jobsite.
- Kept jobsites clean which resulted in higher customer satisfaction.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Coding Bootcamp Certificate | August 2021 University of New Hampshire, Durham, NH A 6-month program for Full Stack Web Development. Utilizing continuous learning of technical programming skills including HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, Handelbars.js, React.js, GraphQL, MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose, jQuery, & Bootstrap among other technologies and frameworks.